Alberto Sonnino

https://sonnino.com

Personal Data

PLACE & DATE OF BIRTH: Brussels, Belgium | 12 February 1992

LOCATION: London, United Kingdom

PHONE AND EMAIL: +44 20 7679 0293 | alberto.sonnino@ucl.ac.uk

Interests

My main research interests are in privacy enhancing technologies, distributed ledgers, and cryptography. I have a special interest in trusted hardware and FPGA-based security applications. In the past, I worked on numerical calculations and simulations for physics-related problems (plasma physics, category theory, symmetry groups).

EXPERIENCES

 $2019 - {\bf Research \ Scientist}, \ {\bf Facebook}, \ {\bf London} \ ({\bf United \ Kingdom}).$

Blockchain Team.

2017 - **Teaching Assistant**, University College London, London (United Kingdom).

Introduction to Computer Science, Introduction to Security.

2008 - 2017 Private Teacher, London (United Kingdom).

Mathematics, chemistry, physics, electricity/electronics, and computer science.

2016 - 2017 Internal Security, Smals, Brussels (Belgium).

National cybersecurity – focus on protection of social and health care data.

2013 - 2014 Coach and Trainer, Catholic University of Louvain, Louvain-La-Neuve (Belgium).

 $\ \, \text{University water-polo team, winner of the National Inter-University Tournament 2013-2014}.$

2008 - 2011 Water-Polo Player, Royal Brussel Poseidon, Brussels (Belgium).

Member of the water-polo team ROYAL BRUSSEL POSEIDON, 1st National League.

EDUCATION

2017 - University College London (UCL), London, United Kingdom.

Ph.D, SECURITY ENGINEERING.

2015 - 2016 University College London (UCL), London, United Kingdom.

 ${\bf Master\ Degree,\ Information\ Security.}$

2013 - 2015 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Karlsruhe, Germany.

Master Degree, Elektrotechnik und Informationstechnik.

2013 - 2015 Catholic University of Louvain (UCLouvain), Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium.

Master Degree, Electrical Engineering.

2010 - 2013 Catholic University of Louvain (UCLouvain), Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium.

Bachelor Degree, Engineering.

LANGUAGES

FRENCH: Native ENGLISH: Fluent DUTCH: Scolar Level ITALIAN: Native GERMAN: Intermediate SPANISH: Basic Knowledge

References

Available on demand.